# ANKIT RAI

3308079098, 8109687159 ■ 2.ankitrai@gmail.com ■ http://ankitrai.com

## **Summary**

I am a Software Engineer having a rich experience in building Java applications who works effectively in a dynamic environment bringing about 2.5 years in software development. Experienced in OOP design, algorithms, data structures, J2EE.

# **Skills & Expertise**

- Java
- J2EE: Servlets & JSP
- Spring MVC, Hibernate
- SQL, PL/SQL
- Data Structures, Algorithms
- HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, Angular-JS, Bootstrap, Foundation
- Apache Tomcat, WebLogic, WebSphere

# **Experience**

Amdocs - May 2015 - Present

<u>Designation</u> - Software Developer

<u>Technology Used</u> • Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JavaScript, Oracle, WebLogic, IBM WebSphere, Serena Dimensions.

• At Amdocs, I am responsible for providing level three support to mission critical BSS applications for telecom domain.

# Tata Consultancy Services Limited • Dec 2012 – Apr 2015

<u>Designation</u> - Systems Engineer

<u>Technology Used</u> • Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Ajax, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON, Oracle, WebLogic, Tomcat, SVN.

- At TCS, I was responsible for developing and architecting web applications while working with other developers to build technical solutions & complete projects to budgetary and quality requirements.
- Developed core modules of a diamond grading and taxation applications.
- Wrote maintainable, extensible and efficient code in a team environment.
- Consulted regularly with customers on project status, proposals and technical issues.

### **Certifications**

Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 6 Programmer, 2010

# **Personal Projects**

Password-Pro Manager
https://github.com/a2ankitrai/Password-ProManager

A Java FX application to store and manage passwords. The application demonstrates features like Java 8 lambdas, JAX etc.

#### **Education**

## B.E. - Computer Science and Engineering

Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal • 2008 – 2012

#### **AISSCE**

CBSE • 2008

Scored 82% marks.

#### **AISSE**

CBSE • 2006

Scored 83.8% marks.

## Strengths

Advanced critical thinking

Leadership Quality & Problem Solving attitude

Quick learner & eager to learn new technologies

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 18 Feb 1991

Languages Known : English, Hindi, Spanish

Passport Available : Yes

Contact : +91-8308079098, +91-8109687159

Email Address : <u>a2.ankitrai@gmail.com</u>Website : <u>www.ankitrai.com</u>

Home Address : C-23, Shankaracharya Homes,

Bag-Sevania, Bhopal-462043 (M.P.)